

# Adam Hayward

### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SMU Coding Boot Camp alumni and professional manager with vast experience in IT. Full stack developer proficient with React and Node.js. Experienced in creating REST APIs to interact with SQL and NoSQL databases. Celebrated as a top performer in all former roles, delivering value through efficiency and possessing a passion for being creative.

### CONTACT

**PHONE** (214) 244 · 1199

EMAIL adam@MeetAdamHayward.com

**WEBSITE**www.MeetAdamHayward.com

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERTISE

- Leadership
- Communication
- Analytics
- Problem Solving
- Collaboration
- Organization
- Customer Service

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript
Node.Js
React.Js
SQL
Mongo DB
CSS/SCSS
HTML

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### SHOPIFY THEME DEVELOPER

Freelancer | April 2021 - Dec 2021

Created e-commerce websites utilizing *Shopify* for small business owners. Developed custom *Shopify Theme's* to fulfill client expectations and deliver a superior end-user experience. Accustomed clients with *Shopify's* admin and CMS tools to further customize and maintain the site.

• worked extensively with HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, and VUE.js

### SMU CODING BOOT CAMP

Student | Sept 2020 - April 2021

Full Stack Web Development bootcamp with curriculum focused on developing technical skills, as well encompassing topics in agile methodology, computer science, database theory, progressive web apps, and much more.

• achieved certificate; graduated with a 4.0

**AT&T, INC** | June 2012 - Sept 2020

Manager Network Services | Feb 2014 - Sept 2020

Operated a team of over twenty *Service & Delivery Technicians* expanded across Dallas, TX. Led and participated in many cross functional teams to re-engineer business processes impacted by mergers and acquisitions. Performed business analysis and project management tasks including stakeholder management, scheduling, requirements definition, budgeting, etc.

- · identified operational inefficiencies and implemented solution strategies
- served on numerous company committees, campaigns, and projects
- received Extraordinary Impact appraisal ratings for 2014 and 2018

## ADAM HAYWARD

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

### EDUCATION

SMU CODING BOOT CAMP
Southern Methodist University | 2021

ACCELERATED TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE TRAINING Richland Collage | 2015

SILVER HONORS DIPLOMA Broad Run High School | 2008

### ACHOMPLISHMENTS

PMP FORMAL PROJECT MANAGEMENT TRAINING PMI | 2018

LEAN SIX SIGMA COURSE AT&T University | 2018

CERTIFIED DEFENSIVE DRIVING INSTRUCTOR

Smith System Driving Institute | 2018

ELITE MANAGER COURSE AT&T University | 2018

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

TOP IN VOICE OF THE CUSTOMER AWARD
AT&T | 2012 - 2020

EXTRAORDINARY IMPACT
APPRAISAL RATTING
AT&T | 2014 - 2018

TOP PERFORMER AWARD

Bank of America | 2011

EMPLOYEE OF THE YEAR AWARD
GIANT FOOD STORES | 2008



### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE | CONTINUED

Premises Technician | June 2012 - Feb 2014 | Promoted

Installed, troubleshot, and repaired an assortment of IP products and services over fiber optic, twisted pair, coax, and WIFI networks. Preformed a variety of duties with an ever-expanding scope of responsibilities to maintain existent services and integrate new technologies. Consulted and communicated service limitations using terminology understood by the client.

- designated new employee trainer and peer mentor
- · continuously recognized for exceeding organization's quality and efficiency metrics
- promoted to Manager Network Services in only twenty months

### BANK OF AMERICA

Teller | Oct 2010 - Oct 2011

Reputed interpersonal skills and precision processing client account transactions.

- · applied proficient Spanish speaking abilities to communicate and assist in translating
- received Top Performer Award for first place in product and service referrals

### **GIANT FOOD STORES**

Assistant-Front End Manager | Oct 2008 - May 2010

Employer recruited with intent to rise front-end performance and customer satisfaction at a specific location. Achieved success by repetitively analyzing the state of the department, identifying opportunities, and implementing adjustments until acquiring desired results. Sustain performance through strengthened employee trust and instituting culture empathetic to the customer.

- twice advanced to higher volume stores
- received 2008 Employee of the Year award

### HARRIS TEETER SUPERMARKETS | Dec 2006 - Oct 2008

Customer Service Supervisor | June 2007 - Dec 2021

- · Cashier | Mar 2007 June 2007 | Promoted
- · Bagger | Dec 2006 Mar 2007 | Promoted

Supervised front-end employees and assisted store management with numerous administrative duties. Won customer enthusiasm by conveying empathy to resolve concerns, process refunds, and preform various customer service accommodations.

- · assumed the role of Store Accountant during weekends
- promoted to supervisory position in only six months